# **Abrar** Jahin

abrarjahin@outlook.com | 317-941-3702 | Indianpolis, IN | <u>linkedin/ajahin</u> | <u>github/AbrarJahin</u>

## **Profile Summery**

Accomplished **6+ years of experience** in different software development companies and teams where I have solved numerous types of problems efficiently. I have a wide range of skills in **System Design**, **Distributed Systems**, **Software Designing**, **Database Design**, **Backend and Front-end development**.

## Work Experience

#### Purdue School of Engineering and Technology

Graduate Research Assistant - Data Science Research Team

Indianapolis, IN, USA February 2021 – Present

- 1. Architected, developed, and deployed a website (in AWS) for data collection due to creating ML based learning recommender system using **ASP.Net Core**, **PostGRE** and **React.js** which improved the Graph Data collection and modification process faster by **4X** (address- <u>csknowledgegraph.org</u>).
- 2. Building CNN and Graph Neural Network based "Learning Recommender System" for assisting school teachers of USA learning Computer Science easily with Python (TensorFlow 2, Keras, CNN, BiLSTM etc.) which will help thousands of people (ongoing, code can be found in <a href="mailto:this.link">this.link</a>).
- 1. Building a "National Intelligent Alert System" for preventing hate crime for improving the lifestyle of thousands minority in USA with Python (TensorFlow 2) (ongoing).

#### Bangladesh Computer Council (BCC)

Lead Software Engineer (Consultant) - Certificate Authority Solution Team

Dhaka, Bangladesh August 2019 - January 2021

- 1. **Architected** and **developed** a digital (**cryptographic**) **cross-platform** browser-based **plug and play** signing system (PDF and XML) with **ASP.Net Core** for Bangladesh Police and other Bangladesh Gov. organizations which made life easier and faster for *160+ million people* in Bangladesh (demo can be found in here <u>opensigner.bcc-ca.gov.bd</u>).
- 2. Architected, developed, and optimized code for the security backend of the cloud drive for Bangladesh Government employees (website link- <u>drive.egovcloud.gov.bd</u>) which has currently more than **50k users** with PHP Laravel, jQuery and LDAP.
- 3. Project management for improving digital KYC (Know Your Customer) system and digital payment system for Bangladesh Govt. resolved KYC problem of BD govt with **artificial intelligent** facial recognition system (based on **Python OpenCV**) which improves task speed to **5X** where API, web interface and admin panel was developed with **Java Spring Boot** and **jQuery** (bcc-ca.gov.bd).
- 4. Managed a project for improving Bangladesh's national security system with **information retrieval** by **analyzing** Facebook feed with some Al-based tools using R based tool.

#### University of Barisal

IT Engineer (Development) – Software Development Team

Barisal, Bangladesh May 2017 - August 2019

- 1. Improved university management system by developing **web-based ERP** with **ASP.Net Core** and **Angular 2** which **improved work speed** by **3X** by removing manual tasks.
- 2. Modernized subject recommending system for students using **Python** and **Java Spring Boot** which helped **over 8000 students** determine appropriate academic subjects based on **user-based k-nearest neighbor** algorithm.
- 3. Resolved analog data conversion problem with **CNN based OCR** implemented with **Python** which increased work speed by **2X**.

#### ReliSource Technologies Ltd.

Software Engineer – Web and API Development Team

Dhaka, Bangladesh November 2016 – June 2017

- 1. Have improved the legacy codebase of one of the USA's prominent large-scale clinical trial management systems for updating features and improving performance by 1.5X based on ASP.Net, AngularJS, and SignalR.
- 2. Built an online real-time remote conferencing system demo for a client based on ASP.Net Core, SignalR and WebRTC aiming for 3 million+ customers with load balancing.

Nascenia IT

Junior Software Engineer – Web Development Team

Dhaka, Bangladesh

February 2016 – November 2016

1. Improved performance of a **Web Socket** based **real-time messaging system** existing in an **intranet** by **3X** by **improving architecture** for **Telenor**, **Sweden** with **ASP.Net Core** and **SignalR**.

2. Built a web-based **admin panel** for managing real time messages and connected real-time online users using **Java Spring Boot** in Agile software development environment.

Upwork
Professional Freelancer – Web Development Projects

Dhaka, Bangladesh July 2014 – February 2016

- 1. Worked as one of the top web-development freelance in Bangladesh with 100% customer satisfaction with 100% job success.
- 2. Profile link- upwork.com/freelancers/abrarjahin2.

#### Samsung R&D Institute Bangladesh (SRBD)

Dhaka, Bangladesh

Intern - Solutions Team

November 2013 – January 2014

Developed API for an internal management system with PHP, MySQL, jQuery and android which improved work speed by 2X.

### Skills

Languages and Frameworks: ASP.Net Core (Advanced), Java Spring Boot (Intermediate), PHP Laravel (Intermediate), Python (Intermediate), SQL [MsSQL, MySQL & PostgreSQL] (Intermediate), React (Intermediate), Angular (Intermediate)

**Technologies**: AWS, Docker, Jenkins, Apache Kafka, Web Server Management in Linux, Web Socket (SignalR), Digital Signature (BouncyCastle), Machine Learning, Data Visualization, Map (Google map), JIRA, Bash, Git

Other: System Designing, Microservices, Good Communicator

### Education

Purdue School of Engineering (Expected December 2022)

Master of Science in Computer and Information Science

Indianapolis, IN, USA

January 2021 - December 2022

Bangladesh University of Engineering and Technology

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science and Engineering

Dhaka, Bangladesh

January 2010 - September 2015

## Certifications and Outstanding Open-source Works

#### Certifications

- a. IBM Applied Data Science (link)
- b. IBM Data Science (link)
- c. Machine Learning (Stanford Online) (<u>link</u>)

#### Outstanding Open-source projects contributed by me

- a. This ASP.Net Core with Angular Universal project is the 2<sup>nd</sup> most popular collaborative angular universal repository on the internet having more than 1.5k stars where I am the 3<sup>rd</sup> largest contributor- <u>github.com/TrilonIO/aspnetcore-angular-universal</u>
- b. I am also the 3<sup>rd</sup> largest contributor of this **Google repo based on WebRTC** having **650+ stars** github.com/googlecodelabs/webrtc-web

#### Online Profiles

- a. LinkedIn-linkedin.com/in/ajahin
- b. Contributed to many open-source projects on Github <u>github.com/AbrarJahin</u>
- c. Problem Solving Solved 500+ problems in Leetcode <u>leetcode.com/abrarjahin</u>
- d. **Top 3% overall in all developers** in Stackoverflow earned 13k+ points and helped millions of developersstackoverflow.com/users/2193439/abrar-jahin